what is going on everybody phil blackman
with barbadon.com and today we're going
to talk about the strongmen that you
should watch at the 2021 rogue
invitational if you want to learn
anything about that competition just
head over to google type in rogue
invitational bar bend and all of that
information is going to come up we're
going to be covering that event you're
not going to want to miss out this is
going to be an absolutely epic weekend
the countdown is on for the inaugural
strongman contest at the 2021 rogue
invitational 10 of the world's top
strong men will compete on october 29th
and 30th at the dell diamond stadium in
round rock texas for the largest prize
purse in strongman competition history
the event features the highly
anticipated returns of 2019 world
strong's man champion martinez leases
and the former american log lift record
holder rob kearney the rogue
invitational is also the second contest
back for two-time world strongest man
runner-up mateus kalashkowski since he
returned after suffering a tricep injury
here's the roster for the 2021 rogue
invitational strongman contest you got
brian shaw tom stoltman luke stoltman
martinez leases matteos kalejkowski rob
kearney j.f carone mikhail shiblikov
jerry pritchett and alexi novikov all
together the 10 strong men on the
official roster for this event have
seven world's strongest man titles
between them the 2021 rogue invitational
features five events four of which are
not maximal lifts the seer dumbbell
ladder the wheel of pain the yolk carry
an overhead log lift medley and the
stone over hitching post which is an
atlas stone event spectators will be
able to watch the 2021 rogue
invitational via the rogue fitness
youtube channel so if you want to check
that out you absolutely can you can also
stay tuned to bar ben because we will
have coverage of the event all weekend
long so let's talk about the strong men
that you should watch come competition
weekend we got to talk about alexi
novokov the 2020 world's strongest man
has been on a hot streak since failing
to qualify for the 2021 world strongest
man finals he's won the 2021 strongman
classic the world's ultimate strongman
competition and the world's ultimate
strongman strength island contest
novakov is often one of the smaller
athletes in the field he's sub 300
pounds he's only six foot three compared
to the giants that he's competing
against but still his combination of raw
power and agility enables him to put up
stellar performances in contests that
are predominantly medley style events
moving on we're talking about the 2021
world's strongest man champion tom
stoltman betting against the reigning
world's strongest man champion is likely
the wrong move particularly since tom
stoltman has continued to perform well
since that win in august despite a
positive covet 19 test keeping him out
of the 2021 europe's strongest man
competition tom stoltman managed a
runner-up finish at the 2021 giants live
world tour final had he not slipped in
the atlas zone event against singleton
stoutman would have won that event if he
brings that same gusto he brought to
sacramento california for his 2021
world's strongest man win it's doubtful
anyone can get in his way moving on to
brian shaw he may be the oldest man in
the field at age 39 but he is
undoubtedly one of the strongmen goats
and is still posting podium finishes he
was the runner-up at the 2021 world
strongest man contest and at the 2021
shaw classic the man is a beacon of
consistency he has the most consecutive
world strongest man finals appearances
with 13 which he also did consecutively
it's the most of any strong man ever
additionally he has the most world's
strongest man event wins with 59 he's
won 59 events at the world's strongest
man contest shaw is always a safe pick
for a podium finisher as he is surely
going to bring the heat with the biggest
prize pool in the sport ever on the line
let's chat about the return of martinez
lisi's lisi's is hungry to get back into
competition having been absent from
elite strongman contest for the past two
years due to various injuries it's
unclear how he's going to stack up
against the current field however at the
2021 world's strongest man contest where
he was doing facebook livestream
commentary with nick english he
reiterated over and over how excited he
is to step back onto the field of play
and finally you should definitely watch
out for luke stoltman can luke stoleman
win this contest absolutely he has the
momentum on his side coming off big wins
at the 2021 europe's strongest man
competition and the 2021 giants live
world tour finals the rub for the older
stoke man brother however is that none
of the events line up all that well with
his strengths he's arguably the
strongest overhead presser in the field
but the log left event at this contest
is a speed ladder as part of a medley
rather than a max lift similarly the
elephant bar deadlift and the wheel of
pain naturally favor the larger athletes
like his younger brother tom and brian
shaw still
given that he is having one of the best
years if not the best year of his career
he certainly could pull an upset and
score a podium finish on any good day he
is out there ten strong man competing in
five events over two days for the
largest prize purse in strongman
competition history is worth all of the
hype that you may be feeling the events
test maximal strength and agility and
there isn't a clear-cut front-runner for
the title given how stacked the roster
really is the biggest mysteries remain
how lysis will fare in his return and if
kaeliskowski's warm-up at the 2021
world's ultimate strongman contest
prepped him to bring his a-game at the
rogue invitational i'm phil bleckman for
barbin.com thanks for watching we hope
you enjoy the 2021 rogue invitational
with the first ever strongman contest
until next time thanks for watching
you